Derick Fabert

Full Stack Web Developer
Mooresville, IN 46158

(317) 258-0021 glen.fabert@gmail.com github.com/dfabert www.linkedin.com/in/derick-fabert/ dfabert.github.io/DerickFabert

Education

Butler University

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development *December 2020*

Learning full stack web development skills to become a well-rounded web developer.

Purdue University

Bachelor of Science, Meteorology August 2007

Synoptic Meteorology and Forecasting track. Took multiple communications classes to improve speaking abilities.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS
- JavaScript, ¡Query, ES6+
- GIT, Bootstrap, AJAX
- Node, MySql
- Team member development
- Client relations
- Certified Broadcast Meteorologist,
 American Meteorological Society

Recognition

- 2015 Silver Dome Award Best Use of Interactive Media
- 2014 Silver Dome Award
 – Best TV
 Weathercaster

Profile

Full stack web developer with broadcast meteorology and real estate experience. Currently attending Butler's Web Development Bootcamp and previously received a Bachelor of Science in meteorology from Purdue University. Experience includes leadership roles and development of a weather focused website. Successfully led a weather and news team through several severe weather events, including tornadoes, blizzards, and floods. Passionate about client relations, accuracy and safety. Delighted to be returning to the web development world to solve complex problems using my new and old skills in a fast-paced environment.

Experience

<u>Adams/Fairway/Reagan Outdoor Advertising, Indianapolis</u> April 2017 - Present

As Real Estate Manager/Representative, oversaw new build projects from start to finish, searched zoning maps and property for potential areas of growth, and cultivated and fostered relationships with lessors. Maintained responsibilities through a corporate transition in ownership after transferring from a smaller regional office in Illinois (Adams Outdoor Advertising).

WCIA (CBS), Champaign, IL

April 2010 - April 2017

As Chief Meteorologist, led the weather team and general weather product for news, managed high-stress situations (including severe weather and breaking news), and developed and maintained the weather website

University of Illinois, Urbana, IL

April 2011 - April 2017

As an adjunct instructor and career advisor, taught a course in broadcast meteorology, advised students on career options, and worked with professors to develop curriculum for aspiring meteorologists.

Web Development Projects

Day Planner | https://dfabert.github.io/DayPlanner/

- This Day Planner was a project that will allow the user to plan the day ahead. The text boxes turn different colors if they are the current hour, in the future, or in the past.
- Javascript, HTML, and CSS were all used in this project.

NBA Dashboard | https://dfabert.github.io/NBADashboard/index.html

- When the NBA was in full swing, this application gave updates on the current scores, the standings, and upcoming games. It allows the user to pick a favorite team as well to keep track of.
- Javascript, HTML, APIs, and CSS were all used in this project.

Password Generator | https://dfabert.github.io/PasswordGenerator/PasswordGenerator.html

- This application uses alerts to create a complicated password for the user.
- Javascript, HTML, and CSS were all used in this project.

Weather Dashboard | https://dfabert.github.io/WXDashboard/

- Weather forecast display that allows the user to view and save different cities for later viewing.
- Javascript, HTML, and CSS were all used in this project.